<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on DW Blog</title>
    <link>https://dwgoblue.github.io/post/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on DW Blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>© All rights reserved - 2020</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 20 Jan 2021 02:51:49 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://dwgoblue.github.io/post/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Oxygen Regulates Human Pluripotent Stem Cell Metabolic Flux</title>
      <link>https://dwgoblue.github.io/post/oxygen-regulates-human-pluripotent-stem-cell-metabolic-flux/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Jan 2021 02:51:49 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dwgoblue.github.io/post/oxygen-regulates-human-pluripotent-stem-cell-metabolic-flux/</guid>
      <description>Human pluripotent stem cells (hPSC) is assumed to well manage their resources via metabolic machinary for differentiation. In terms of energy production and consumption, oxygen plays a crucial role but is limited in the embryo. Although previous works have investigated metabolism in hPSC with 20% oxygen (atmospheric level), the physiological oxygen level was measured at about 5% which is much lower than the concentration used in the previous experimental setting. To get more percise metabolic dynamics during hPSC development, the auther compared the cells under two different oxygen levels, 5% and 20%.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Matlab Installation in Ubuntu (Ubuntu 20.04.1 LTS)</title>
      <link>https://dwgoblue.github.io/post/matlab-installation-in-ubuntu/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Jan 2021 02:50:19 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dwgoblue.github.io/post/matlab-installation-in-ubuntu/</guid>
      <description>MATLAB installation in Ubuntu (Ubuntu 20.04.1 LTS) Overview MATLAB is a powerful programming language/software when it comes to matrix computing. Although it is not a open-source software, as a bioinformatician, I still need to use it sometimes for my research. In this blog, I will introduce how to install MATLAB in your local machine with Ubuntu as your OS.
Procedure Firstly, we have to download a version of MATLAB that is suitable for your work and your hardware.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ubuntu Notes (keep updating)</title>
      <link>https://dwgoblue.github.io/post/ubuntu-notes/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Jan 2021 02:49:40 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dwgoblue.github.io/post/ubuntu-notes/</guid>
      <description>Overview Installation Issues Reference   Overview Ubuntu is a Linux distribution which is an open-source operating system. Compared to other operating systems, Linux supported by a group of qualified developers offers stable and secure but flexible system for users. In other words, users can customize the OS with any open-source software and modifications of OS itself. Because it does not track any digital footprint, Linux is hard to be hacked by using backdoor and infected by virus.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Jupyterlab on Linux Server</title>
      <link>https://dwgoblue.github.io/post/jupyterlab-on-linux-server/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Jan 2021 02:48:58 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dwgoblue.github.io/post/jupyterlab-on-linux-server/</guid>
      <description>Jupyterlab on linux server  Overview Installation Virtual environment Issues Reference   Overview Jupyterlab is a lightweight but comprehensive and full-development IDE. In addition to write scripts with nice highlights syntax for Python and R as I know, the notebook is probably the most well-known feature with which users are able to write codes along with markdown-style notes. Besides, if you are a user who tends to install as less softwares/packages on your local machine as possible, running Jupyterlab on remote server may be suitable for you.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Chinese Input Methods for Ubuntu</title>
      <link>https://dwgoblue.github.io/post/chinese-input-methods-for-ubuntu/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 20 Dec 2020 02:36:01 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dwgoblue.github.io/post/chinese-input-methods-for-ubuntu/</guid>
      <description>Overview Popular input methods Installation for iBus chewing Issues Additional Reference  Overview As a Taiwanese, Chinese input methods are essential for my daily communication with my friends and family. I used to type Chinese/Mandarin with Microsoft Chinese Pinyin input that is quite good for me. Unfortunately, there is no any alternaltive that has the same performance in Ubuntu or other Linux distro. Reluctantly, we will introduce popular input methods working fine on Ubuntu in this blog, and I will provide the way I followed to install and configure the methods.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Build Github webpage by Hugo</title>
      <link>https://dwgoblue.github.io/post/build-gitpage-by-hugo/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 08 Feb 2020 22:07:46 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dwgoblue.github.io/post/build-gitpage-by-hugo/</guid>
      <description>Overview Github offers users a space to build personal pages. Their initial intention is to encourage users recording and sharing their works on Github so as to make the community thriving. While it should be static site hosting which means a front-end page without connections to backend, one could easily and fast initialize a personal website by build-in template, user-defined projects or static site generators such as Hugo and jekyll. I will focus on Hugo in this article.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>